Professor Louis Kestenberg Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Professor Louis Kestenberg Papers
1948-1965
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Kestenberg, Louis, d. 1982.
13.00 Linear Feet
Dr. Louis Kestenberg taught German at the University of Houston from 1933 until 1974. The collection contains files related to Kestenburg's teaching and activities at the University of Houston as well as his academic interests.
1982-002
Biographical Note
Professor Louis Kestenberg received his A.B. degree from Rice Institute in 1930; his M.A. in German from Rice in 1933; and his Ph.D. in German History from the University of Colorado in 1943. Born in Sosnowiec, Poland in 1907, Kestenberg emigrated with his parents to Houston, Texas in 1920.
Dr. Kestenberg joined the faculty of the University of Houston in 1933 as Instructor in German; became a fulltime faculty member in 1940 and continued to teach at the University of Houston until his retirement in 1974 as Professor Emeritus of History. Professor Kestenberg also served as the Chairman of the Division of Modern Languages from 1950 to1955; he served as First Chairman of the Honors Program from 1957 to 1964; as Visiting Professor at Tulane University in 1948 and as a Fulbright Teaching Interchange Lecturer in Reutlingen, West Germany in 1956 and 1957.
He was also a member of the American Historical Association and the American Association of University Professors and belonged to Phi Kappa Phi, Delta Phi Alpha, and Phi Alpha Theta National Honor Societies. Professor Kestenberg also served as President of the Houston Chapter of the United Nations Association and as President of the Neighborhood Centers Association.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains files related to Kestenburg's teaching and activities at the University of Houston as well as his academic interests.
Forms part of the University Archives.
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
American Association of University Professors--University of Houston Chapter; Phi Kappa Phi; United Nations Association of the United States of America--Houston chapter; University of Houston--Dept. of History
Genre/Form of Material:
Clippings; Faculty papers; Records
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Acquisition
Detailed Description
- University of Houston Subject Files
  This series contains 52 folders related to Professor Kestenberg's association with the University of Houston. Included are materials concerning his participation with the Faculty Association, Faculty Club, and Phi Kappa Phi. The folders are primarily arranged alphabetically by subject or organization title, then chronologically if necessary. Dates in this series range from 1948-1981.
  - Correspondence, Inquiries, Replies, 1969-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Association, 1950- 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Club, 1950- 1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Club Committee, 1950- 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - History Department, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - History Department, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History Department Executive Committee, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - History Department Executive Committee, 1971-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History Department: Graduate Faculty, 1965- 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - History Department: Graduate Faculty, 1971- 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - History Department Recommendations Memos, 1954-1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - History Department Recommendations Memos, 1962-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - History: Graduate Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - History Majors-Undergraduates, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - History 379A Tests and Assignments, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Honors Class, Spring, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Honors Day, 1955-1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Honors Program, 1957-1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Honors Program, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Honors Program, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Honors Program, 1974-1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Honors Program Council, 1959-1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Honors Programs: Student Directories Average, 1957-1962 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Honors Programs: Student Directories Average, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Honors Programs: Student Directories Average, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Honor Societies, Phi Kappa Phi, Freshman, Senior, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Inauguration of President W.W. Kemmerer, 1952- 1953 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - International Relations Club, 1948-1949, 1957- 1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Kestenberg Papers; Donitz: I II, 1957- 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Kestenberg Papers; Donitz: I II, 1975- 1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Kestenberg Papers; Outlines, Notes Used, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Leadership Conference, October 16-17, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - M.A., Ph.D., Fields, Exams, Notes and Records, 1946-1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - M.A., Ph.D., Fields, Exams, Notes and Records, 1967-1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - M.A. Thesis Topics, Style Sheets and Manual, 1966-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Ph.D. Admission Requirement Committees, 1964- 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Ph.D. Admission Requirement Committees, 1973- 1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Phi Kappa Phi, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Phi Kappa Phi, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Phi Kappa Phi, American Historical Association, 1958-1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Phi Kappa Phi, Distinguished Graduating Seniors, 1965- 1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Phi Kappa Phi, Distinguished Graduating Seniors, 1971- 1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Phi Kappa Phi, Distinguished Graduating Seniors, 1975- 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Phi Kappa Phi, Distinguished Graduating Seniors, 1977- 1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Phi Kappa Phi, Faculty Nomination, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Phi Kappa Phi, Senior Scholastic Society, 1946-1957 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Phi Kappa Phi, Senior Scholastic Society, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Phi Kappa Phi, University of Houston Chapter, 1974- 1975 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Phi Kappa Phi, University of Houston Chapter, 1976- 1981 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Ransom Award: Kestenberg, 1968- 1974 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Thesis Committees, 1968-1974 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Subject Files
  This series is the largest in the Collection and contains two hundred and seventy two folders. Folders are in alphabetical order by subject, then chronologically where necessary. The material in these folders contains items used by Professor Kestenberg in his classes and as research for his own purposes. A large portion of this series includes material related to Germany (history and politics) and to the United Nations Association.
  - AJP Taylor; Hoggan; Origins of WWII; Dolchstol, 1956- 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - A League of Nations, 1920- 1923 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - America, 1950s (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - American Friends Service Committee (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Area Language Studies, 1944-1951 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Arizona; Background Papers, 1977- 1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Arts Sciences Faculty Meetings, 1952- 1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Assistants; Graders, 1957- 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Atlantic Union, 1943- 1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Atlantic Union, 1959- 1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Auschwitz Buchenwald Dachau KZs, 1956- 1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Aus Politik Und Zeit Geschichte, 1956- 1962 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Aus Politik Und Zeit Geschichte, 1963- 1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Aus Politik Und Zeit Geschichte, 1965- 1969 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Aus Politik Und Zeit Geschichte, 1970- 1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Basques, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Berlin, 1948- 1959 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Berlin, 1960- 1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Bibliographies, 1943- 1972 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Bibliographies, 1945- 1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographies: Germany History, newspapers, journals, etc, 1961- 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Bonn, 1948- 1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bormann, (nd) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - British Information Services, 1954- 1955 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Bundesarchiv, Notes and Outlines, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Bundesarchiv, Photocopier, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Bundesverfassungsgericht, 1974- 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Bundeswehr, 1962- 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Cartoons - Diagrams - Photos, 1950- 1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Charta der deutschen Hematvertriebenen, 1950- 1952 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Chronologies, 1940s- 1960s (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Chronologies, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Committee on Advanced Hours and Minors, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Common Market, 1949- 1973 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Conferences, 1941- 1978 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Conferences - Geneva, 1953- 1955 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Consulting-Marquart Company, 1967-1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Contemporary Germany: Culture, 1965- 1975 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Contemporary Germany: Culture, 1976- 1981 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Curriculum Suggestions, 1945- 1962 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Data Used, 1949- 1979 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Denazification, 1945- 1950 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Dismemberment; Order - Meisse, 1948- 1953 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Dismemberment; Order - Meisse, 1954- 1973 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Dolchstosz - Verrat, 1963- 1968 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Donitz, Clippings, 1974- 1981 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Donitz Correspondence, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Donitz: Number Trails Salewski (1943 takeover), 1945- 1974 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Donitz Regierung, Notes, (A-J), 1960-1971 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Donitz Regierung, Notes, (A-J), 1960-1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Donitz Regierung, (K-Z), 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Donitz Regierung, (K-Z), 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Donitz Regierung: Uncond'l Surdr, 1948- 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - East Berlin, 1965- 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - East Europe, 1960- 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - East Germany No. 1, 1940s (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - East Germany No. 2, 1950s (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - East Germany No. 3, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - East Germany No. 4, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - East Germany No. 3, 1951- 1964 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Economics, 1947-1953 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Economics, 1954-1959 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Eichmann Trail, 1960- 1967 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Eichmann Trail, 1972- 1980 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Europe: Education (1) Bibliography (2) Vocabulary, (since 1945), (1960-1968) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - European Recovery: Marshall Plan, 1947- 1949 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - European Studies, 1957- 1962 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - European Studies, 1963- 1980 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Facts and Figures about Germany's Refugee and Expellee Problem, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - France, 1950s (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - France, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - France Germany, 1948- 1958 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - France Germany, 1959- 1966 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - France Germany, 1967- 1981 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Free Mind, 1978- 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - German Americanisms, 1971- 1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - German Club, 1947- 1950 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - German Club, 1951- 1954 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - German Club Notices, 1949- 1954 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - German History Reading Lists, Ph.D, Topics since (1914) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Germans on America, 1955- 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Germany, 1975- 1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Germany Adenauer, 1949- 1959 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Germany Adenauer, 1960- 1976 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Germany: Anglo- German Relas, 1954- 1979 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Germany Bibl.: Bibliographies, outlines, abbreviations, 1952- 1973 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Germany Cultural (1), 1940s (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Germany Cultural (2), 1950s (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Germany Cultural (3), 1960s (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Germany Cultural (4), 1960s (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Germany Cultural (5), 1970s (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Germany: Education, (since1945), (1957- 1969) (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Germany Education: Administration, (since 1945), (1955- 1975) (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Germany Education: Circulation, (since 1945), (1952- 1967) (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Germany Education: Extra - Curriculum, (since 1945), (1951- 1973) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Germany Education: Extra - Curriculum, (since 1945), (1972- 1973) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Germany Education: Finance, (since 1945), (1953- 1973) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Germany Education: Pedagogy, (since 1945), (1953- 1978) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Germany Education: Vocational, (since 1945), (1956- 1966) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Germany Education: Volkshochschule Adult Education, (since 1945), (1951- 1974) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Germany: Foreign Evaluations, 1963- 1975 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Germany: Foreign Policy, 1963- 1966 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Germany: Nuclear Deterrent, 1956- 1968 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Germany: Rearmament, 1950- 1978 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Germany: Weimar Era Communist Party, 1962- 1980 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Germany since 1945, 1940s- 1950s (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Germany since 1945, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Germany since 1945, 1960s cont. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Germany since 1945, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Germany since 1945, 1970s cont. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Germany since 1945, 1980s (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Germany since 1965, 1949- 1966 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Germany since 1965, 1967- 1977 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Germany since 1945: Archives Chicago Center, 1949- 1975 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Germany since 1945: Bader- Meinhoff, 1972- 1976 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Germany since 1945: Bader- Meinhoff, 1977- 1978 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Germany since 1945: Bader- Meinhoff, 1979- 1981 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Germany since 1945: Bibliographies, 1963- 1975 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Germany since 1945: Bundestag -- Bundesrat, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Germany since 1945: Bundestag -- Bundesrat, 1969- 1981 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Germany since 1945: Churches, Concordat, 1970- 1976 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Germany since 1945: Communist Party in West Germany, 1967- 1978 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Germany since 1945- 1965: East Germany, 1958- 1975 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Germany since 1945: East Germany, 1974- 1981 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Germany since 1945: Economics, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Germany since 1945: Economics, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Germany since 1945: Economics, 1977- 1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Germany since 1945: Education, History, 1973- 1978 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Germany since 1945: Education-Reform, 1972- 1978 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Germany since 1945: European Unification, 1950- 1955 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Germany since 1945: European Unification, 1960- 1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Germany since 1945: Formation of Bundesrepublik, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Germany since 1945: Gastarbeiter, 1973- 1981 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Germany since 1945: Grundgesetz, 1966- 1978 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Germany since 1945: Grundgesetz (const'n), 1951- 1978 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Germany since 1945: Historiography, 1964- 1972 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Germany since 1945: Historiography, 1973- 1981 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Germany since 1945: Hitler Bibliography, 1934- 1973 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Germany since 1945: Hitler Bibliography, 1973- 1980 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Germany since 1945: Int'l Schulbuch (UNESCO) UN University, 1972- 1980 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Germany since 1945: Israeli-German Relations, 1971- 1981 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Germany since 1945: Jews, K-Z, No. 1, 1952- 1969 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Germany since 1945: Jews, K-Z, No. 2, 1970- 1981 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Germany since 1945: Politics Building (Folder # 2), 1955- 1973 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Germany since 1945: Politische Building, 1962- 1972 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Germany since 1945: Problems Reform No. 1, 1969- 1970 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Germany since 1945: Problems Reform No. 2, 1971- 1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Germany since 1945: Reutlingen, 1938- 1963 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Germany since 1945: West Berlin, 1945- 1970 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Germany since 1945: West Berlin, 1971- 1981 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Germany since 1945: World War II, 1918- 1959 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Germany since 1945: World War II, 1960- 1969 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Germany since 1945: World War II, 1970- 1981 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Hitler: Biographical II, 1963- 1981 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - International Conferences: Bermuda Berlin, 1953- 1954 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - International Conferences: Geneva Caracas, 1954- 1955 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Israel - Zionism - PLO - Terrorism, 1972- 1977 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Israel - Zionism - PLO - Terrorism, 1978- 1981 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Kirchen im III. Reich, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Kultasministeriamkouferenz, 1966- 1978 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Labor - Gewerkschaft, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - McGovern, 1971- 1972 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Microfilm German Records; Serials, 1955- 1970 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Modern Language Division, 1945-1955 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - MSI: Claghorn MS; (copies), 1967- 1979 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Nazi Economics, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Nazi Propaganda, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Nazi Sterilization, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Net Archives: Microsoft No. T-77; Ft. Worth N/A Steinert (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Bibliography; NYX's Index, 1970- 1972 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - North Atlantic Pact, 1949- 1966 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - NYT Bank, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Pius XII; Hochuth's Stellurtr, 1964- 1975 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Press and Information Office, 1971- 1973 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Quotations, 1968- 1971 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Radio Programs: German, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Recommendations Written, 1951-1978 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Reference Guild to the United Nations, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Roehm, 1957- 1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Schwerin Von Krosigk: Eiserner Vorhong, 1961- 1973 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Simon Wiesenthal Center - Holocaust, 1980- 1982 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Speer - Reviews, 1948- 1971 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Sponsored Classes: Socratic Society, 1941- 1946 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Southwestern Democrats (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - S. S., 1970 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Sweden, 1948- 1950 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - T.A.G.S., 1953-1955 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Texas Education Agency, 1962-1970 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - The New York Times: Annual Education Review, January 16, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - The Red, White and Blue Series, 1917- 1918 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Third Annual HAMUN Delegate Handbook, April 13- 15, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Thomas Mann the Third Reich, 1937- 1973 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - United Nations, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - United Nations, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - United Nations, Abbreviations, Personnel Rank, 1970- 1975 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - United Nations, Achievements Pamphlets, 1945- 1979 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - UN: Acronyms, 1950- 1980 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - UN: Addresses, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - UN: Bibliographies, Outlines, Correspondence, 1941- 1977 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - UN: Books Publications, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - UN: Brochures, 1947- 1954 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - UN: Budget, Finance, 1960- 1981 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - UN: Colonialism; 3rd World, 1974- 1980 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - UN: Ecology (Demography), 1974- 1979 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - UN: Evaluation, Philosophy, Hopes, 1957- 1979 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - UN: FACT Sheet, 1971- 1979 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - UN: FAO, 1971- 1979 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - UN: Geneva Conference, 1973- 1977 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - UN: Historical Data, 1941- 1976 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - UN: Human Rights, 1975- 1978 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - UN: ILO, 1959- 1980 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - UN: International Court of Justice, 1973- 1980 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - United Nations Minutes, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - United Nations Minutes, 1967-1968 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - UN: Law of Sea; Seabed, 1968- 1974 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - UN: Law of Sea; Seabed, 1975- 1981 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - UN: Multinationals; Transnational, 1972- 1981 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - UN: Newspaper Clippings, 1945- 1963 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - UN: Organizations, Achievements, Problems, and Materials, 1949- 1963 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - UN: Organizations, Achievements, Problems, and Materials, 1964- 1975 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - UN: Peacekeeping; Truce; Observer, 1961- 1980 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - UN: Potpourri: Problems Women; Slams; Habitat Interpreters (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - WMO, 1954- 1981 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - United Nations: President, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - UN: Problems, 1980- 1981 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - UN: Security Council General Assembly, 1950- 1980 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - UN: Security - General, 1963- 1981 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - UN: Specialized Agencies, 1949- 1980 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - UH: United Nations University (UNESCO); correspondence, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - UN Vienna, 1976- 1980 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - UN: Who, 1973- 1981 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - United Nations Association, 1970-1974 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - United Nations Association: Annual Meeting, 1980- 1981 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - UNA: HAMUN, 1977- 1979 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - UNA: High School Contest Essay Contest Winners, 1963- 1980 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - UNA: History, 1951- 1963 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - UNA: History, 1963- 1979 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - UNA: Ho. Charter, 1976- 1978 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - UNA: Ho. Charter, 1978- 1980 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - United Nations Association: Houston Chapter, 1976- 1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - UNA: 32nd 33rd Issues, 1977- 1979 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - UNA: Newsletters, Memberships, Board of Directors, 1954- 1970 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - UNESCO, 1946- 1961 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - UNESCO, 1962- 1981 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - UNESCO- Pamphlets, 1964- 1978 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - University of Maine at Orono Conferences and Institutes, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Untitled Newspapers Clippings, 1955-1963 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Untitled Newspapers Clippings, 1964-1973 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - U. S. Germany, 1945- 1955 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - U. S. Germany, 1956- 1966 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - U. S. Germany, 1967- 1980 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - U. S. S. R., 1950s (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - U. S. S. R, 1960s (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - US UN, 1947- 1981 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - War Guilt, 1939- 1973 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - War Information Series, 1917- 1918 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Weimar/Bonn, 1945- 1974 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Weimar Republic, 1950s (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Weimar Republic, 1960s (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Weimar Republic, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Welfare - Family - Youth, 1962- 1965 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - What To Do with Germany?, 1945- 1968 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Women, 1961- 1968 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - World Bank, 1969- 1981 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - World Literacy Day, 1971- 1978 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - World Peace Foundation Pamphlets, 1915- 1924 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Year, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Yugoslavia, 1948- 1955 (Box 13, Folder 11)